the first step of this
exercise is just to get the value of
key b so we've got a hash here on line
one
and we want to retrieve the value
associated with the key
that is the symbol b we can
do this using element reference
when working with a hash we can access a
value
by passing in a key to these square
brackets
so we know we want to access the value
associated with the key
b and on line three i'm going to use
p to output this so we can see the value
we expect that it'll be two
and that's what we see
the next step here is to add to the hash
a new key value pair
and to do this we'll use element
assignment
in the square brackets we'll place the
new key
and we'll assign this to whatever value
we want associated with that key
in this case the integer 5.
now on line 7 i'll output our hash
and we expect to see five key value
pairs
and that's what we see
the last step here is to remove all key
value pairs
whose value is less than 3.5
and to do this we can use the delete
if method
as the delete if method iterates through
our hash
each key value pair will be passed as
arguments to the block
our block parameter k will be assigned
to reference the key
and our block parameter v will reference
the value
[Music]
now the delete if method deletes every
key value pair
from the hash for which the return value
of the block
evaluates as true so if the return value
of this block is truthy
that key value pair will be deleted from
our hash
and because we know we want to delete
the key value pair if the value is less
than 3.5
we can do a simple comparison here on
line 9.
this will return a boolean either true
or false
and if it returns true that key value
pair will be deleted from our hash
so on line 12 we'll output our hash one
last time
on the third line of output you can see
that our hash has been
mutated destructively by the delete if
method
the only remaining key value pairs in
our hash
are those with values greater than 3.5